-爸爸 -你怎么起来了
- Daddy. - What are you doing up?
我睡不着
I can't sleep.
等等 你在我睡觉时吃东西吗
Wait. You eat while I'm in bed?
你们都背着我加餐吗
Is there a meal I don't know about?
加一两餐吧
A couple.
但你该就寝了 小家伙
But you need to hit the hay, buddy.
我要你鼾声如雷到辰时
I need you sawin' logs until 0700.
整段话我都不知道是什么意思
I don't know what any of that means.
最近 我和歌洛莉亚之间的"热情"有点冷却
Gloria and I are going through a romantic dry spell.
幸好 她今晚跟她朋友丽贝卡出去
Luckily, she's out tonight with her friend, Rebecca,
那女的嫁了个渣男
who is married to a jackass.
歌洛莉亚每次跟她见完面 都看我很顺眼
Gloria always comes home ready to show her appreciation.
忽然之间 我穿着袜子上床睡觉
Suddenly, me going to bed with socks on
也没那么十恶不赦了
is not such a deal-breaker.
我靠
Aw, geez.
我回来了 杰
I'm home! Hey, Jay.
丽贝卡怎么样了
How's Rebecca?
她现在登上人生巅峰
She's never been better.
她一个月前离开了她老公
So, she left her husband like a month ago,
简直就像从肩膀上卸下了一个重担
and it's like a weight has been lifted off her shoulders.
说到肩膀
Speaking of shoulders,
你准备好享受我拿手的"按摩"了吗
are you ready for one of my famous massages?
不用了
No, I'm good.
是她打来
It's her.
喂
Hello?
那个服务生吗
The waiter?
我就知道他是在撩你
I knew he was flirting with you!
别忘了她嫁的那个草包
Don't forget about that clod she married!
你算是觅得良缘了
You got one of the good guys!
而且他不用写下来都能记住我们点的菜
And he didn't have to write down our order,
他以后肯定也不会忘了你的生日
so you know that he won't forget your birthday.
乔把所有玩具都丢在地上了
Joe leaves all his toys on the floor.
我叫他捡起来 但他都不听话
I tell him to pick them up, but he doesn't listen.
我跟你说 卧室里就是一场灾难
I'm telling you, it's a disaster in the bedroom.
我不知道如何是好
I don't know what to do.
就像是他不记得"东西"该往哪儿塞
It's like he can't remember where things go.
最终 我沮丧失望
Eventually, I get so frustrated
只好自己"搞定"了
that I take care of it myself.
打屁股
Spanking?
行吧 或许可以试试这招
Well, yeah, I guess we could try that.
其实你说起这事
Actually, now that you mention it,
哈维尔和我很久以前也试过
Javier and I tried it a long time ago.
确实改变局面了
It was a game-changer.
丽贝卡现在过得很好
Ay. Rebecca is doing so well.
听起来她在纵享人生
Sounds like she's having fun.
海军过去强迫我们看关于她那种女人的电影
Navy used to make us watch films about girls like that.
她老公从来都没真正满足过她的需求
Well, her husband never really gave her what she needed.
她有告诉他吗
Did she tell him?
没有 但有时跟一个不用你说
No. But sometimes it's more exciting to be with someone
就知道你想要什么的人在一起 比较刺激
that already knows what you want without you telling them.
懂了
Got it.
喂
Ay! Hey!
搞什么啊
Wh-What the hell was that?!
没什么 你知道吗
Nothing! You know what?
我好像忘记锁大门了
I think I forgot to lock the front door.
-他回来啦 -别生气
- There he is. - Oh, now, don't get mad.
我知道我之前说只会为派对买郁金香
I know I said I was only getting tulips for the party,
但我豪气了一把 买了兰花
but I splurged and I got orchids.
-我也希望这个派对与众不同啊 -好吧
- I -- I wanted the party to be special, too. ?- Okay.
我解释一下 我之前不知道你会买兰花
And in my defense, I didn't know about the orchids.
我买了台钢琴
I got a piano.
真的吗 在哪里
Really, where?
我最近得到了一份很体面的工作
I recently got a pretty fancy job
给亿万富翁迈克尔·奎因利打工
working for billionaire Michael Quinly.
-有点厉害 -就是很厉害
- It's kind of a big deal. - It is a big deal.
我承认 举办派对
Now, admittedly, throwing a party
庆祝自己走好运了 可能有点炫耀的意味
to celebrate your own reversal of fortune could be seen as braggy.
有点算是灰姑娘卖瓜了
Sort of a rags-to-bitches story, if you will.
但话说回头 之前好一阵
Then again, for a while now,
每当我告诉朋友我为工作烦恼时
when I've been telling my friends that I was struggling,
他们都会露出"那个眼神"
they'd give me "That look" --
大部分是同情
the one that's mostly sympathetic
但又掺杂了一丝看好戏的感觉
with just a touch of enjoying my pain.
所以今天 我会得到另一种眼神
So, today, I get the other look --
大部分是"我真为你高兴"
the one that's mostly "I'm so happy for you"
但又掺杂了一丝"妒忌使我丑陋"的感觉
with just a hint of "I am wracked with jealousy."
见到以前那群朋友会很开心的
It'll be good to see the old gang again.
-是啊 没错 -嗯
- Yeah. Yeah, yeah. - Yeah.
你好呀
Hey, you.
你在干嘛 跟男生发短信吗
What's going on? You, uh -- you texting a boy?
只是在考虑我夏天的计划
Just figuring out my summer plans.
我还记得我大一那年的夏天
I remember the summer of my junior year.
我跟着NWA乐队的巡演
I followed N.W.A. on tour --
NWA就是"弹手风琴的内村人"
Nebraskans With Accordions.
当然了 这是团员惨遭谋杀之前的事了
This was before Polka Pete was brutally murdered, of course.
我的有点不同
Yeah, this is a little different.
事实上我想去麻省理工实习
I'm actually up for an internship
研究最小超对称标准模型
researching the minimal supersymmetric standard model at M.I.T.
酷哦 去波士顿
Cool. Beantown.
我不知道我为什么像小女生一样紧张期待
I don't know why I'm getting all girly and excited about it.
反正我也不可能得到这个机会
It's not like I'm gonna get it anyways.
怎么说丧气话呢 如果你想听我的建议...
What's with the quitter talk? If you want my advice --
并不想 不过谢了
No, I don't, but thanks.
怎么一堆垃圾食品
What is all this junk?
水果卷 薯片 巧克力牛奶
Fruit Roll-ups, chips, chocolate milk? Ugh.
冰箱里啥吃的都没有
Th-There's nothing in the fridge.
我给你准备一盒午餐带走
I'm packing you a lunch.
我总是听说人生到了某个阶段
I've always heard there comes a time in life
就会变成由孩子反过来照顾父母
when the kid starts parenting the parents.
我本来以为那是我40岁之后才会发生的事
I thought it would be when I was in my 40s.
但我有超越年龄的成熟
But I'm pretty mature for my age,
而我爸拿到薯格都会开心地拍手
and my dad claps when he gets waffle fries.
你为什么还在家里
What are you even still doing home?
平时这会儿你不是已经去魔术店了吗
Don't you usually open your magic shop by now?
对 我只是晚去一点
Yeah. I'm just going in a little late.
听起来对生意可不好
Doesn't sound good for business.
而且我看到你偷偷把胡萝卜从午餐里取出来了
And I saw you sneak those carrots out of your lunch.
我是想避开另一位店主
I'm trying to avoid one of the other shop owners.
那家伙有点吓人
Kind of an intimidating character.
一切始于一个停车位引发的争执
It started with a dispute over a parking space
之后矛盾就升级了
and escalated from there.
我们家的人从来不躲避恶霸
Hey...we don't avoid bullies in this family.
我们勇敢面对他们
We stand up to them.
去吧
Off you go.
我想你没意识到我面对的是什么狠角色
I don't think you realize what kind of person I'm up against.
昨天 他把我全部恶作剧漏洞杯
Yesterday, all my dribble glasses
全换成了真杯子
were replaced with real ones.
丢死人了
It was humiliating.
朗吉 我们得好好聊聊最近的事
So, Long', we have a lot to catch up on.
-最近怎么样[什么升了] -我的体重没升
- What's up? - Not my weight.
汤姆·布拉迪节食法改变了我看待世界的方式
The Tom Brady diet changed the way I see the world.
食物 非食物 超级食物 毒药
Food, not food, super-food, poison.
你的新鲜事就聊完了
Oh, well, okay, that covers you.
我想问你近况
I was going to ask about you,
但你知道 我总是为你的答案紧张
but, you know, I'm always nervous about the answer.
我们来碰碰运气吧
Well, you know what? Let's roll the dice.
-原来我... -米奇
- So, it turns out that I -- - Hey, Mitch.
小卡在哪
Where's Cam?
克莱尔 真是惊喜
Claire, what a surprise.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
是你让我给你带钢琴曲的
You asked me to bring over the piano music.
《派对时光最爱金曲》
"Party-time Favorites."
天啊 真是无巧不成书啊
Oh, my gosh, how apropos.
我去放在家里的新钢琴上
I'll just set these on our new piano... ?
这我刚好会的乐器上
...that I know how to play.
派对很棒 各位
Great party, boys.
这钢琴这么显眼不聊不行吧
We need to talk about the piano in the room.
好吧 是这样
Uh, well, yes, so, okay, okay.
小卡一直想要一台钢琴
So, Cam has always wanted one,
说实话 我们一直负担不起
and frankly, it has been out of our price range
直到这周
until this week.
有趣的故事 原来我...
Fun story. It turns out that I --
我真没礼貌
I'm being rude.
我是山姆·特恩布尔
Sam Turnbull.
我是克莱尔·邓菲
Oh! Claire Dunphy.
你是《洛杉矶女性》杂志的编辑 对吧
Hi. You are the editor of L.A. Woman magazine, right?
发音应该是"拉乌芒"[法语]
I believe it's pronounced "La Woman."
才不是
It isn't.
真有趣 因为你办公室上周给我公司打了电话
It's funny because your office called my business last week.
貌似我出现在《商业女性》特辑的
Apparently, I'm on some short list
最终候选人名单上
for the Women in Business issue.
-是橱柜业吧 -是的
- Closets, right? - Yeah.
我打破女人无法在高位的"玻璃天花板"
I shattered the glass ceiling --
很讽刺的是 我们出了一款新的玻璃天花板橱柜
and ironically, we have a new glass-ceiling closet.
你穿衣服时能看外面是否下雨
You can see if it's raining when you're getting dressed.
会拯救许多小山羊皮
Gonna save a lot of suede.
今年竞争很激烈啊
Well, it's, um, pretty competitive this year.
我要去找钢琴另一边的人聊聊天
Anyway, I'm meeting someone on the other side of the piano.
我该走了
I should leave now.
我都对他的傻逼杂志没兴趣
I don't even care about his stupid magazine,
但被他这么甩脸就走...
but to be dismissed like that?
各位 感谢你们光临寒舍
Hey, everyone, everyone. Thank you so much for coming.
大家现在都好难有机会见面
We never get to see each other anymore,
大家的生活都很忙
what with our busy lives.
乔撒姆忙于环境音乐作曲
And Jotham's ambient music compositions,
迪帕克致力于游击园艺
and, uh, Deepak's guerrilla gardening,
还有我和我的新工作
and, well, me and my big new job
老板是迈克尔·奎恩利
working for Michael Quinly.
是啊
Yeah.
在各大博物馆都能看到他名字的有钱人吗
The rich guy whose name is on all those museums?
还有医院 敬我们所有人
And hospitals, yeah. So, to all of us!
恭喜啊
Ah, congratulations.
真棒 我们都
It's really great. We're all --
我们都为你高兴
We're all so happy for you.
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
你看见了大家的表情 对吧
You saw the look, right?
完全是爱和支持 夹杂了一丝讨厌的嫉妒
Pure love and support with just a hint of rancid envy.
来聊聊
A word.
但我正在爽呢 小卡
But I'm basking. Um, Cam.
你说话时我上了网
So, while you were talking, I got online,
你的新老板被发现挪用公款了
and...your new boss was caught embezzling.
你的公司要倒闭了
Your company is crumbling.
不不 这事不能又发生在我身上
No! No! This -- This can't be happening to me again.
相信我 你会找到别的工作
You know what? You'll find something else.
天啊 小卡 我十秒前
Oh, my -- Cam, I literally
刚吹嘘了一份并不存在的工作
just bragged about a job that doesn't exist.
好吧 他们不能发现这事
Okay, okay. They cannot know,
否则这会变成同情派对
or else this will turn into an actual pity party.
好 交给我吧
Okay. Yeah. Yeah, yeah. I-I got this.
各位
Hi, everyone.
我们要更深层 更私密地
So, we are about to get to know one another on a deeper,
了解彼此
more personal level.
我想你们都知道这个碗是装什么的
I think you all know what the bowl is for.
不 不是钥匙 乔撒姆
Hey, no. Not your keys, Jotham.
是手机
Your phones!
我们要重拾失落已久的谈话艺术
We are about to rediscover the long-lost art of conversation.
如果保姆打来电话呢
What if the sitter calls?
你的狗狗会没事的 先生们 请交出手机
Your dog will be fine. Phones, gentlemen, phones.
你周六都上班吗
You're working on a Saturday?
我在面对一点小问题
I've been dealing with a little problem.
这种时候 我只会去一个地方寻求帮助
In moments like this, there's only one place I turn.
我受宠若惊 爸爸
Well, I am flattered, Dad.
好吧
Right.
既然你在这里
Hey, but, you know, since you're here...
这话题很难开口
Uh, it's a difficult subject.
歌洛莉亚和我的
Gloria and I...
床事有点问题
...having an issue in the bedroom.
好吧
Okay.
速度和强度都不如从前
There's been a drop-off of pace and intensity.
我了解到她想要
I get the impression she's looking for,
换换口味
maybe, a little more variety.
但也不能怪她
But you can't blame her.
我的那几招从70年代开始就一直在用
I've been using the same moves since the '70s.
我干脆加点70年代舞步进去得了
I may as well be doing "The Hustle" in there.
我要润润嗓子
I'm just gonna wet my whistle.
我听见她昨晚跟她的朋友说
I heard her tell her friend last night
想被打屁股
about wanting to be spanked.
不久后 机会出现在眼前
And later, the opportunity presented itself, and...
不 你没有 你没有
No, you didn't. You didn't.
-三次 -天啊 为什么是三次 爸爸
- Three times. - Oh, God. Why three times, Dad?
我不知道 也许因为多年来
I don't know. Maybe all those years of ping-pong
我在仓库打了不少乒乓球 手腕很灵活
in the warehouse. I've got very agile wrists.
但我不知道该怎么挽回这场面了
But I don't know how I come back from this one.
爸爸
Well, uh, Dad, when you, um --
当你对歌洛莉亚做那件事时
When you did what you did to Gloria,
你让性爱的重点全聚焦在她身体上了
you made the sex all about her body,
而女人希望能照顾到她们心灵
and a woman wants it to be about the mind.
糟糕 我就害怕是这种狗屁
Oh, crap. I was afraid it would be about that sort of thing.
听着 她是个聪明有趣的女人
Look, she is an intelligent, interesting woman.
你得提醒她你注意到了这些
And you just need to remind her that you notice that --
不像是《洛杉矶女性》杂志
unlike, say, I don't know, L.A. Woman magazine,
只关注女人的外表
that only cares about how a woman looks.
所以不聊我的事了
So, we're off my thing, huh?
没错 希望永远别再提
Hopefully forever, yes.
我今天在小卡和米奇那
I ran into the editor of that magazine
碰到了那个杂志的编辑 你知道吗
over at Cam and Mitch's today, and you know what?
他上下打量我
He looks me up and down.
突然我就不在他们的商界女士名单上了
Suddenly, I am off their women-in-business list.
现在《洛杉矶女性》有自己的杂志啦
So, L.A. Woman is its own magazine now?
我记得它以前是在《洛杉矶男性》的末尾
I remember when it was the back page of L.A. Man.
我想我是没琳达·沃恩那么美
Well, I suppose I'm just not as glamorous as Linda Vaughn,
矫正鞋女王
the queen of corrective shoes.
这和你穿的
And this has nothing to do with the fact that you showed up
像刚给马喂过水一样有关吧
looking like someone who just watered some horses?
那又怎样 实力呢
Who cares? What about merit?
我知道 但你得遵守游戏规则
I hear you. But you got to play the game.
我上《橱柜日报》
I didn't get on the cover
78年9月的封面
of Closet Time's September '78 issue
可不是因为穿了不合身的牛仔裤
by wearing Jordache jeans one size too big.
我才不这样
I'm not doing it.
他们搞他们的选美比赛吧
They can keep their beauty contest.
我不在乎
I don't care.
在你说不之前 先看看这个
Before you say "No", take a look at this.
这不能证明你要证明的 爸
It's not making the case you think it's making, Dad.
天啊
Oh, God.
所有的手机都在这了
Okay, that's all the phones.
在聚会结束前
Look, nobody's gonna find out about you losing your job
不会有人发现你失业了
until after the party.
好 我去开门
Okay, I'm -- I'm gonna get that.
你打电话退了
You call someone about returning the piano
我们承担不起的钢琴
we can no longer afford.
其实你的新工作也养不起它
Well, we couldn't really afford it with your new job, either.
你怎么不回我短信
Why haven't you been texting me back?
-你心里鄙视我们呢吧 -没
- You're judging us, aren't you? ?- No.
这和我听说的你俩做的
This is nothing compared to the things that I have heard
-根本没法比 -好吧 等下
- that you two do - Okay, whoa, whoa, whoa.
我没看到你的短信
I-I never saw your text, okay?
我们电话都放在大碗里
All of our phones are in a bowl.
是"那种"聚会啊
Oh, it's that kind of party.
你觉得我们在干啥啊
What do you think that we do?
我遇到问题了
I have a problem.
等会吧 我有客人呢
Well, can it wait? I have guests.
你爸打我屁屁
Your father spanked me.
自助餐 他们可以自助啦
Eh, it's a buffet. They'll be fine.
我和钢琴公司说了
Okay, I talked to the piano company --
嗯 我爸打她屁屁了 我们就说到这
Okay, okay, my dad spanked her. You're all caught up.
-什么 -你做什么了
- What? - What did you do?
我大叫 然后他跑了
I screamed, he ran away.
现在我觉得他有点窘迫
And now I think he's embarrassed.
好吧 好吧
Okay, okay.
不晓得真假 但有时人们这么对别人
For what it's worth, sometimes people do things to other people
可能是希望别人这么对自己
that they want done to themselves.
有时 连续好多年
Sometimes, for years on end.
真的吗
Really?
你觉得杰想让我打他屁屁
So, you think that Jay wants me to spank him?
如果他像我交往过的
Well, if he's like some of the successful,
那些成功男士 那就是的
powerful men I've been with, yes.
-那些男士是谁 -我不做的事是哪些
- Who are those men? - What are these things I don't do?
我想我可以问问那是不是他想要的
Well, I guess I could ask him if that's what he wants.
不不不 别那么做
No, no, no, no, no. Don't do that.
他可能已经觉得难为情了
He's probably already feeling self-conscious.
自然点 就好像没发生过一样
Act casual, like it never happened.
我做得到
I can do that.
你们这个超级大的钢琴
I haven't even said anything
我就什么都没说
about this gigantic piano you have here.
如果今天退不了 它就真属于咱们了
Okay. Well, if it doesn't go back today, we own it,
搬家公司马上就到
so the moving company is on the way.
我觉得我们的客人会看到的
Okay, well, I think our guests are gonna notice that,
可能会好奇为什么
maybe ask a question or two.
我来处理
I've got this.
各位 各位
Hey, guys. Hi, guys.
米奇尔和我
Mitchell and I...
可能就只有小卡 还不确定
Or maybe just Cam. Not sure yet.
要重新装修我们的浴室 我们想问
...are about to remodel our bathroom, and we were wondering,
有哪位对于室内装修有强烈看法
does anyone here have strong opinions about interior design?
好的 请各位跟我来
Okay. Can you guys, uh, follow me right this way?
都请进 空间很大的
All right, everybody in. Yep, there's plenty of room.
我关上门
And I'll -- I'll just close the door,
给你们点空间 这样就能畅所欲言
give you guys some privacy so you can speak freely.
好啦
There you go.
好啦 看啊
All right. And, oh, look at that.
门把手掉了
The...doorknob came off.
你们等下 我去修一下
Sit tight. I got to fix this.
爸
Hey, Dad.
宝贝 你在这干嘛
Hey, sweetie. What are you doing here?
你真觉得我不会发现这些胡萝卜吗
Did you really think I wouldn't notice these?
还有 我拿到了那个实习机会
Also, I got that internship.
需要你在保险单上签个字
I just need your signature on my insurance form.
我和你说了要保持乐观
I told you to stay positive.
这会多么有趣呀
How much fun is this gonna be?
这跟有趣完全无关
It's really not about fun.
会有很多辛苦的工作
It's gonna be a lot of hard work.
压力爆表
The pressure's off the charts.
难怪有心理健康免责同意书
Well, that would explain the mental-health waiver.
上一个他们录取的大学生完全崩溃了
The last undergrad they let into the program completely snapped.
他们发现她在自由之路[观光行程]上
They found her wandering the Freedom Trail
啥也没穿就戴个护眼镜瞎逛
wearing nothing but her safety goggles.
邓菲 你又占了我的位置
Dunphy, you're in my spot again.
-就是她 -她就是欺负你的家伙吗
- That's her. - She's your bully?
你知道她根本就没多壮吧
You realize she's not even that big, right?
只是头发蓬
It's mostly just hair.
这矮冬瓜是谁
Who's the jock?
斯蒂芬妮 这是我女儿艾丽克斯
Oh, Stephanie, this is my daughter Alex.
艾丽克斯 这是斯蒂芬妮
Uh, Alex, this is Stephanie.
她是隔壁棋盘游戏店的老板
She owns the board-game shop next door.
对 我卖卡牌游戏《魔法风云会》[魔术集合]
Yeah. I sell "Magic: The Gathering",
他卖魔术 但没人来集合
and he sells magic, and no one is gathering.
要不要这样
Come on.
爸 记得我们聊过的吗
Dad, remember what we talked about.
记得 严格来说
Oh, yeah. Technically...
9号位是个共享的停车位
...spot nine is a shared parking space.
看谁消失的球[胆子]回来了
Ooh, look whose disappearing balls came back.
我们通过新出的珍藏版
What do you say we settle this once and for all
《巫师和术士》来永久解决这个问题吧
with the newly released collector's edition
你觉得怎么样
of "Wizards and Warlocks"?
来吧
Set her up.
我受够你的欺负了
I'm done being pushed around by you.
谁赢了车位就归谁
Winner gets the spot.
这是个角色扮演游戏
It's a role-playing game.
我是佐艾尔 十九级巫师
I'm Zorel, a 19th-level wizard
有三十个金元宝和一头曾是我儿子的牛
with 30 gold ingots and a cow who used to be my son.
这游戏我熟 我可是加州理工的学生
I'm familiar with the game. I go to Cal-Tech.
发明这游戏的人去年给我们做了毕业演讲
The guy who invented it gave our commencement speech last year.
来吧 邓菲
Okay, Dunphy.
接着上次玩 你卖了你的长剑
When we left off, you had just sold your long sword
-买了些豆子 -本可能是魔豆的
- for some beans. - Which could've been magic.
从没有迹象表明那是魔豆
There was no indication of that.
爸 你的金子都哪去了
Dad, where's all your gold?
我发现佐艾尔不喜欢被太多身外之物
I found that Zorel doesn't like to be weighed down
拖慢脚步
by too many worldly possessions.
但胜负的关键是尽快掠夺并用金子换武器
But the key is to pillage early and trade your gold for weapons
赶在范维寇大门打开放出食人魔之前换好
before the Van Wickle gates open and the ogres are released.
诅咒卡 你的双手变成蹄子了
Curse card. Your hands are now hooves.
该你扔了
Your roll.
但先让我做个提议
Uh, but first, a proposal --
用我的盾换你的羽毛帽
my shield for your feathered cap.
我看不下去了 骰子给我 起来
I can't watch this. Give me those. Up.
我知道你的打算了
Ah, I see where you're going with this --
你要呼吁议会长老召开和平会议
calling for a peace conference with the council of elders.
不 我要把议会长老送到船上
No. I'm putting the council of elders on our ships
烧死他们 扔吧
and burning them. Go.
我在这 随意读读杂志 杰
I'm here, casually reading a magazine, Jay.
不愧是我的天才
There's my brainiac.
你都不用回头看
You didn't even have to turn around.
就知道是我
You knew it was me.
曼尼在学校
Oh, well, Manny's at school,
乔又没有钥匙
and Joe doesn't have a key, so...
你在研读什么
What are you tearing through?
没什么 不过是本时尚杂志
Nothing. Just, like, a fashion magazine.
英语的 你的第二语言
In English, your second language.
你脑袋里有那么多信息
With all that information in your head,
我们该叫你"百事通布朗"[棕色]
we should be calling you "Encyclopedia Brown" --
我这么说可与你的肤色无关
which sounds like a slur, but isn't.
你肯定能帮我解决
Hey, I'll bet you can help
一个困扰了我很久的难题
me with something I've been struggling with.
我看不太可能
I doubt it.
让我惊喜一下 出手吧
Give me a thrill. Take a whack at it.
你到底想让我做什么
What exactly do you want me to do?
我相信你能解读这个线索
I'm sure you can figure out this clue.
来 就填一行[打一下] 帮我开个头
Come on, one across. Help me get started.
什么鬼
What the hell?!
我会整理房间的 我保证
I'll clean my room, I promise!
可恶
Damn it.
你到达埃克斯莫尔峰会了
You made it to the Summit of Exmore.
真有那个峰会吗
It exists?
如果我想得到这个实习机会
I need to get these forms in by 5:00
我得在五点前把表格送到
if I'm gonna take this internship,
我当然想得到
which I obviously am
因为我已经为这努力一辈子了
because I've been working for this my entire life.
爸 交给你了 你基本上稳赢不输了
Dad, take over. You're basically in an unlosable position.
你来到了一个十字路口
You appear to be at a crossroads --
在峰会大门与守卫决斗
battle the guards at the summit gate
还是进入未知领域的传送门
or take a portal to lands unknown.
如果是已知领域就好决定多了
This would be so much easier if it was lands known.
你不是真的在犹豫吧
You're not actually struggling with this, are you?
但假如传送门把我送去特别酷的地方呢
But what if the portal leads to someplace really cool?
你去了峰会就赢了
You win by getting to the summit.
那个传送门有62%的机会
There's a 62% chance that portal
直接把你送回草原
leads right back to the meadow.
那是数学
That's math.
而你身在魔法之屋
You're in a house of...magic.
你回到草原了
And you're back in the meadow.
你是怎么想的
What were you thinking?
没关系 传说
It's fine. You know, legend has it,
有一颗毒蘑菇下面有捷径
there's a shortcut under one of the toadstools there.
走捷径怎么能赢
You don't win by taking shortcuts!
领先才能赢 我帮你领先了
You win by taking the lead -- which is what I did for you
我有系统地爬上高山
by methodically clawing up the mountain,
无情地击败你的敌人
ruthlessly defeating your enemies,
然后赢得胜利
and then emerging victorious --
而不是在草原上犹豫不决
not dithering around in some meadow!
我出去抽会电子烟
I'm gonna step out for a vape break
让你俩解决一下问题
while you two sort this out.
你知道我为什么喜欢草原吗
You know why I like the meadow?
因为那里能让我思考下一步怎么走
'Cause it lets me think about what I want to do next.
我该和食人魔大战
Should I battle the ogre
还是勇敢面对绝望之沼
or brave the Swamps of Despair?
我该接受波士顿压力超大的实习机会
Should I take the super stressful internship in Boston,
还是说我争取机会只因为我应该争取
or am I doing that just because I think I'm supposed to?
我击败了几百个候选人
I beat out hundreds of candidates.
我能与这个领域的杰出学者共事
I would be working with the pre-eminent scholar in the field.
这是一生难逢的机会
This is the chance of a lifetime.
是啊 但这是你的一生
Yeah, but it's your lifetime.
你享受一下也可以的
It's okay to enjoy it.
没人会拒绝这机会
No one turns this down.
你总是喜欢做第一个尝试某件事的人
Well, you always liked being the first one to do something.
过个你想过的夏天吧
Give yourself the summer you want.
你已经收集了够多的金元宝
You've collected enough gold ingots
足够让你休息一下了
to buy yourself some time off.
我不会因此变懒的 对吧
It won't make me lazy, will it?
亲爱的 你六个月就会走路
Honey, you walked at six months,
一岁就会说话 而你的第一句话是
spoke at a year, and your first words were
"抱歉我这么久才学会走路"
"Sorry it took me so long to walk."
好了 钢琴搬走了
Okay, so, the piano's gone.
顺带一提 刚才那声音
Oh, by the way, that sound you heard
是货车屁股与地面摩擦的声音
was the bottom of the truck scraping against the street,
-这... -好了
- so... - Okay, yeah.
我说不好 小卡 这样他们会信吗
Yeah, I don't know, Cam. Is this really gonna sell it?
会信的 我在我三十六年的人生中学到了
Yes, it is. I've learned in my 36 years that,
先自欺就能欺人
if you believe a lie, others will, too.
-好了 把客人们放出来吧 -好
- Okay, release the guests. - Okay.
都修好了
Okay, all fixed.
我就知道 抗焦虑药白吃了
Figures. Just as your Xanax is kicking in.
大伙 听我说
Hey, guys, so, listen.
天这么好我们却把你们关了那么久
We've kept you cooped up on this beautiful day.
不如我们把派对变成花园派对吧
Why don't we turn this party into a garden party?
你的钢琴怎么用床单盖住了
Why is your piano covered with a sheet?
因为官方是这么建议的
Oh, um, well, because they recommend it.
他们说这样的新钢琴哪怕受五分钟阳光直射
They say even five minutes of direct sunlight on a new piano
钢琴键盘也会变得像
like this, your keyboard turns into something like
英国人的烂牙一样
an English person's teeth, so...
-大家为什么不 -是啊
- Okay, well, so why doesn't everyone just... - ?Yeah.
大家拿上小零食跟已经开瓶了的酒
...grab some appetizers and any wine that's already opened...
-已经开瓶的酒 -然后我们就...
- Already opened wine. - ...and we'll --
大家安安
Hello, boys.
你来这里干嘛
What are you doing here?
你没收到我的短信吗
Didn't you get my text?
没有啊 我们所有人手机都放碗里了
No, all of our phones are in a bowl.
-变态 -不是下流的...
- Ew. - It's not dirty...
不像你的裙子好吗
unlike that dress.
你好啊 山姆
Hi, Sam.
我的妈啊
Oh, my God.
好吧 你就这么想上人家杂志吗
Okay, you're that desperate to get into the magazine.
不是 我要让他露出伪君子的真面目
No. I am going to expose him for the fraud that he is.
他假惺惺地说他的宝贝名单纯看个人表现
He claims that his precious little list is merit-based.
而当我穿运动裤时 他没兴趣
When I was wearing sweatpants, he wasn't interested.
现在我盛装打扮了一下...
Now that I've gussied up a little...
他就会把你放上封面吗
He's gonna put you on the cover.
真的吗 你真这么觉得吗 别说了
Really? Do you think? Shut up.
小卡 我刚才被困在卫生间里时
Hey, Cam, there was an article in an old Details magazine
在旧杂志上读到一篇文章
I was reading in your bathroom
在说我们应该支持自己的朋友
about the need to support your friends.
我们都想听你弹奏
We do want to hear you play.
-别了吧 各位 -别了 别了吧 大家
- No, you know what? - Let's not. Let's not.
人家只是过了想弹的时候了
I just don't even feel like I'm in the mood anymore.
你撒谎的本事比你的身形还大
You're a bigger liar than your scale.
-来啦 -就一首
- Come on. - One song.
没到你弹完之前 大家都不许走
No one gets to leave this room until you do.
那好吧
Okay, well...
我想说 你看起来好美
I must say, you do look beautiful.
让我想起我第一次留的胡子
You remind me of my first beard.
谢谢
Thank you.
我是个出门是贵妇 房中是荡妇的奇女子
I'm a lady in the streets and a freak in the spreadsheets.
这也不算是个坏标题啊 如果你还有兴趣
It's not a bad caption, if you're still interested
把我加到你的杂志的话
in using me in your magazine.
听起来有点... 单薄
Sounds a little... thin.
是啊 顶级的琴都是这样
Oh, well, all the best ones do.
你可能听习惯了便宜 音场饱满的那种
You're probably used to a cheaper, fuller-sounding,
无覆盖钢琴了
uncovered piano.
? 又一个新郎 又一个新娘 ?
? Another bride, another groom ?
电影《一曲相思情未了》的歌
Oh, from "Fabulous Baker Boys."
? 又一场和煦的蜜月 ?
? Another sunny honeymoon ?
太性感的一部电影了
What a sexy movie.
当米歇尔·法伊弗首次
When Michelle Pfeiffer first...
跳入我们的心
...leapt into our hearts.
等等 钢琴上哪去了
Wait, where's the piano?
我... 我没事 谢谢关心
I'm -- I'm fine, by the way.
我们把钢琴弄走了
So, we did get rid of the piano.
因为我们供不起了
Um, we -- we can't afford it anymore.
我得到的那个好工作 又没了
That great job that I had? Uh, I lost it.
所以...
So...
我之前对我朋友的评价真是大错特错
I couldn't have been more wrong about our friends.
的确 他们有时候挺尖酸刻薄
I mean, yes, yes, they can be snarky at times,
但当我们真的需要他们支持鼓励时
but when I really needed their support,
他们也对我们献出全心全意
they were completely there for me.
或许你应该重新审视自己人生
You know, you should take a look at your life
看看是什么让你这么难以信任别人
and see what happened to make you so untrusting.
是应该反省了
I should. G-Gaw!
然后想到我们还把人家都锁厕所里
And to think we -- we locked them in that bathroom
也没个理由或通知
for no reason.
肯定也不好受吧
That couldn't have been fun.
是啊
Yeah, I know.
这件事也曾经发生在我身上过 还记得吗
Uh, the same thing happened to me once, remember?
就是有一次门把真的意外掉下来了
When that -- the handle accidentally fell off.
就是... 就是我们第一次吵架那晚
The -- The -- The night of our first fight.
是啊 好像记得吧
Yeah. Yeah, vaguely.
那是意外不是人为 对吧
That was an accident, right?
-小卡 -你把门把修好了吗
- Cam. - Did you fix the door knob yet?
再一会儿 宝贝
Just another minute, sweetie.
小卡
Cam!
我跟乔谈过了
I talked to Joe
谈了他看到的事
about what he saw,
他现在不害怕了
and he's not scared anymore.
很好 那你也能让我不怕吗
Great. Can you do the same for me?
抱歉我不该打你啦
I'm sorry I did that to you,
但我真的以为你想要玩那个嘛
but I really thought that that's what you wanted
因为你也是这么打我啊
because that's what you did to me.
但我是因为听到了
But I heard you tell
你跟朋友说打屁股会有帮助啊
Rebecca you thought that spanking would help.
是对管教乔要打扫房间
With Joe and his room.
所以我们这是一场误会
So...it was a misunderstanding.
是啊
Exactly.
所以我们的床事没有缺少什么
So, there's nothing missing from our love life.
-是的 -那就好
-Right. - Right.
但你懂 虽然说没缺少什么
Yeah, but, you know, that nothing is missing
但这不代表不能加点新花样进去啊
doesn't mean that we cannot add a little something to it.
是啊 我老实说
Yes, I'm being honest.
我的确是有一点想点的"曲目"
I've got a...few requests for the band.
比如呢
Like what?
我觉得说出口有点怪
You know, I feel weird talking about it.
要不我们写下有兴趣的项目
Why don't we write some of this stuff down,
丢进帽子里 然后抽签决定吧
toss it in a hat, and see what we pull out?
这条你很快啊
You fired that right off.
你那个感觉很有意思
That one sounds fun.
不许偷看
No peeking.
我说过我会做那条了
Ay, I said I was gonna do that one.
是啊
Right.
-我们上楼进房说吧 -好
- Let's take it upstairs. - Okay.
-这是什么 -我知道了
- What's this? - Oh, you know what?
这帽子本来是曼尼在玩猜电影名游戏用的
I think that is the hat that Manny uses to play charades.
那就好 因为我可没这柔软度
That's a relief, because I don't think I'm flexible enough
做出什么《飞天万能车》式
for a "Chitty Chitty Bang Bang."
准备好来第二轮了吗
You ready for round two?
当然啦
Of course I am.
你在被子里干嘛
What are you doing down there?
单子写着我的左脚啊
It says My Left Foot.
你抽到的是电影《我的左脚》
You got another movie.
天啊 真是太爽了 这招式叫什么啊
God, that was amazing. What do you call that?
叫《飞天万能车》
That's a chitty chitty bang bang.
你确定吗
You sure about this?
亲爱的 别让我有反悔的机会啊
Honey, don't give me a chance to change my mind.
我是佐艾尔 一个5级巫师
I'm Zorel, a 5th-level wizard
草原之王
Master of the meadow.
准你戴着胡子
You can keep the beard,
但你不许说话
but no talking.